lashback.com 2010-12-31

# LashBack: Global Email Compliance

Thank you for your interest in LASHBACK (“LASHBACK”) and our website located at www.LASHBACK.com. We are pleased to provide this privacy policy to inform you of our practices with respect to how we collect and use personally identifiable information about visitors to our website. By using this website, you consent to the following terms. 

**What we collect**  
The only personally identifiable information that we require about you is your contact information (e.g., name, address, telephone number, e-mail) and unique identifier (e.g., password). If you purchase any of our products or services, we will also collect financial information (e.g., credit card number). We also collect IP addresses, but this information generally does not reveal your identity. 

**How we collect it**  
We collect your personally identifiable information when you use the website, complete the registration form, or purchase any of the products or services offered on our website.

**Cookies**  
To facilitate your use of our website, we may use “cookies.” A cookie is small amount of data that our servers transfer to your browser and that only our servers can read. When you log onto this website, the cookie file captures your username, unique session identifier number and other session data to enable you to traverse through this website’s various screens without having to authenticate yourself at each new screen. 

**Use of Information**  
We uses your personally identifiable information to: (1) verify your authority to access this website, (2) provide you with access to any services that you may chose to subscribe to, (3) process and ship any products that you purchase through our website, and (4) contact you when reasonably necessary. We may also use any information you have entered into the website as reasonably necessary to administer or provide customer support for the website and our products and services.

**Non-Disclosure**  
LASHBACK will not sell or rent your Personal Information, nor will LASHBACK provide to third parties your Personal Information unless LASHBACK has your consent (which LASHBACK may infer has been granted based on circumstances of use of Lashback.com and specific product requests) and (1) sharing your Personal Information is required to provide the product or service you have requested, or (2) LASHBACK needs to send your Personal Information to companies which work on its behalf in order to provide you a product or service (which companies will not have any right to use your Personal Information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist LASHBACK). LASHBACK will disclose your Personal Information to the extent required in the event it must respond to subpoenas, court orders or other legal process, or if LASHBACK finds that your actions on LashBack.com violate any terms of use, any usage guidelines for specific products or services, or any terms of any license agreements you agree to.

**Links**  
For your convenience, we may provide links to certain third party websites or referrals to certain third parties’ products or services. If you choose to visit a third party’s website or use its products or services, please be aware that the third party’s privacy policy, and not this Privacy Policy, will govern your activities and any information you disclose while interacting with the third party.

**Security**  
We employ procedural and technological measures, consistent with the demands of customer service, reasonably designed to protect your personally identifiable information from loss or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. Where reasonably practical, we use encryption, password protection and other security technology (e.g. Secure Socket Layer) to help prevent unauthorized access to your personally identifiable information.

**Policy Changes**  
We reserve the right to change this privacy policy, and will post any revisions on its website located at www.LASHBACK.com. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes. Your continued use of this web site will be subject to the then-current privacy policy.

Safe Harbor Privacy Statement

**SafeSafe Harbor Standards**  
This Safe Harbor Privacy Statement (the "Statement") sets forth the privacy principles followed by LashBack LLC. (LASHBACK) in connection with the transfer and protection of "personal information" received from the European Union (EU) or Switzerland. 

**About The Safe Harbor**  
The "Safe Harbor" program was jointly established in June 2000 by the United States Department of Commerce and the European Commission, as a method for transferring personal information from the European Union (EU), to companies in the United States. The program is a voluntary self-certification process for companies operating in the United States. Companies that certify represent that they are upholding privacy standards for personal information received from the EU that have been jointly accepted by the EU Commission and the US Department of Commerce. These standards exceed current US privacy standards. LASHBACK has certified to the Safe Harbor program and makes that commitment. 

"Personal Information" means information that can directly or indirectly lead to the identification of a living person, such as an individual's name, address, e-mail, telephone number, license number, medical identification number, photograph, or other identifying characteristic. The identification can occur by reference to one or more factors specific to the individual's physical, physiological, mental, economic, cultural or social identity. Personal information does not include information that has been anonymized, encoded or otherwise stripped of its identifiers, or information that is publicly available, unless combined with other non-public personal information. 

**Scope**  
This Statement governs personal information transferred from countries in the EU or Switzerland (which has adopted substantially similar privacy laws to those of the EU), to the United States on behalf of LASHBACK. It applies to personal information in electronic and off-line formats.

**Safe Harbor Privacy Principles**  
The following privacy principles apply to the transfer, collection, use or disclosure of personal information from the EU by LASHBACK.

**Notice:** LASHBACK informs individuals in the EU about the purposes for which it collects and uses their personal information, how to contact LASHBACK, the types of third parties with which LASHBACK shares their personal information, and the choice and means LASHBACK offers for limiting the use and disclosure of their personal information. 

Consistent with the Safe Harbor requirements, LASHBACK may not be in a position to furnish notice in certain limited situations. Specifically, notice is not required where the processing of EU personal information is necessary to respond to a government inquiry; is required by applicable laws, court orders or government regulations; or is necessary to protect LASHBACK' legal interests and providing notice would interfere with those interests. 

**Choice:** LASHBACK will not process personal information about EU individuals for purposes other than those for which the information was originally obtained or subsequently authorized by the EU individual unless the individual affirmatively and explicitly consents ("opt-in") to the processing, or unless an exception applies. LASHBACK also provides EU individuals with the opportunity to withdraw consent at any time ("opt-out"), in which case their personal information will not be further processed. There are certain limitations on the right to opt-out, such as those that apply in the clinical research situation. In that situation, LASHBACK can continue to rely upon personal information already provided by clinical research participants who choose to discontinue participation in a clinical trial, to the extent needed to protect the integrity of the study, but cannot collect any additional personal information about that individual once the written request to withdraw participation is received. 

**Data Integrity:** LASHBACK seeks to ensure that any personal information held about EU individuals is accurate, complete, current and otherwise reliable in relation to the purposes for which the information was obtained. LASHBACK collects personal information that is adequate, relevant and not excessive for the purposes for which it is to be processed. EU individuals have a responsibility to assist LASHBACK in maintaining accurate, complete and current personal information about them. 

**Transfers To Third Parties:** LASHBACK will only transfer personal information about EU individuals to third-parties where the third-party (a) has provided satisfactory assurances to LASHBACK that it will protect the information consistently with this Statement; or (b) is located in the EU or a country considered "adequate" for privacy by the EU Commission, and therefore is required to comply with the EU data protection laws or substantially equivalent privacy laws; or (c) the third-party has also certified to the Safe Harbor, and is accordingly independently responsible for complying with the Safe Harbor requirements. 

Where LASHBACK has knowledge that a third-party to whom it has provided EU personal information is processing that information in a manner contrary to this Statement or the Safe Harbor requirements, LASHBACK will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop the processing. 

**Access And Correction:** Upon written request to LASHBACK, LASHBACK will provide EU individuals with reasonable access to their personal information. LASHBACK will also take reasonable steps to allow EU individuals to review their information for the purposes of correcting their information. There are certain limitations to the Access and Correction rights, as set forth in the US Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor website. 

**Security:** LASHBACK takes reasonable precautions to protect EU personal information in its possession from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. 

**Enforcement:** LASHBACK has established internal mechanisms to verify its ongoing adherence to this Statement. LASHBACK also encourages individuals covered by this Statement to raise any concerns about our processing of their personal information by contacting LASHBACK' Privacy Office at the address below or by contacting their local privacy officer or Legal Department. LASHBACK will seek to resolve any concerns. LASHBACK has also agreed to participate in the dispute resolution program provided by the European Data Protection Authorities. 

**Limitation On Scope Of Principles:** Adherence to these Privacy Principles may be limited to the extent required to meet a legal, governmental, national security or public interest obligation. 

**Contact Information:** Questions or comments about this Statement should be directed to:  
LASHBACK LLC  
ATTN: Privacy Dept.  
555 Washington Avenue  
Suite 400  
Saint Louis, MO 63101 

**Better Business Bureau (BBB) Dispute Resolution Process**  
In order to comply with the European Union’s Safe Harbor Principles, LashBack commits to the resolution of complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. We have committed to resolve any complaints by European Union citizens relating to this policy, which cannot be resolved directly with our company, through BBB EU Safe Harbor, a dispute resolution procedure administered by the Council of Better Business Bureaus, Inc.

If you have any questions regarding this policy, please contact:

LashBack LLC  
555 Washington Avenue  
Suite 400  
ATTN: Safe Harbor Admin.  
Saint Louis, MO 63101

SafeHarbor at lashback dot com

If you do not receive acknowledgment of your complaint or your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by business name, you should then contact:

Council of Better Business Bureaus, Inc.  
BBB EU Safe Harbor  
4200 Wilson Boulevard, Suite 800  
Arlington, VA 22203  
Phone: 703-276-0100  
Web: www. us.bbb.org  
Email: [eusafeharbor@council.bbb.org](mailto:eusafeharbor@council.bbb.org)
